

Michel de Graaf michel@re-invention.nl http://re-invention.nl +31 (0) 6 36 42 74 07

Michel de Graaf Software Engineer

About me: Fullstack software engineer with over 17 years of experience shipping complex software solutions.

My strength lies in architecting and developing new products from concept to production (MVP) or upgrading existing projects to the latest development stack in the cloud with professional software engineering practices such as Automated Testing (BDD/TDD), Continuous Integration, Continuous Delivery and Infrastructure Monitoring with a pragmatic eye on scaling your architecture for future growth.

- Specialised in architecting and developing advanced web applications and web services (REST, GraphQL).
- Integrating different software systems with each other and managing data flows (REST, SOAP, GraphQL)
- Developing advanced user interfaces using Javascript (ES6, Typescript, React, React-native, Flux, Redux, Elm, Apollo) on the web and mobile devices.
- Scaling and deploying applications in the cloud (AWS, ECS, Docker, Elastic beanstalk, Kubernetes, Terraform).
- Setting up a professional software engineering pipeline (Continuous Integration, Continuous Delivery).
- Strong interest and knowledge of computer security (Fuzzing, Pentesting) and Linux ninja.

My approach to software craftsmanship is test-driven (TDD), agile, and using the best tool for the job. I favor a SCRUM/Agile-driven project and have experience managing projects using this methodology.

Experience

2004 - Current, Re-invention (Founder)

My consultancy company: specialized in advanced (web-based) software solutions

2022 - 2023, IKEA - Tech Lead & Product owner (Freelance)

Developing & leading the technical implementation of the IKEA Content Coworker Experience program with the goal of helping coworkers in sales with finding their way to information so they can do their job better by utilizing knowledge graph technology. Tech used: Neo4J, Typescript, React, Azure, NodeJS, Continuous integration, Continuous delivery.

2022 - Current, hypotheekrente.nl - Software engineer (Freelancer))

Developing a lead processing system for mortgage advisors. Tech used: Ruby on Rails, Typescript, Apollo, GraphQL, Docker, CI/CD/GITOPS, k8s.

2019 - 2022, ING / Homerun / Homigo - CTO (Freelancer)

Homerun is a corporate startup backed by ING Neo. Its core product is a SaaS productivity tool (mobile/web) for contractors/homeowners to manage home renovations. This makes for an exciting and technically challenging feature set of advanced real-time chat, dropbox-like filesharing, resource/activity planning, and other domain-specific features. Tech used: Ruby on Rails, TypeScript, React(native), Apollo, GraphQL, Docker, Continuous integration, Continuous delivery.

2016 - 2019, BEEQUIP - Interim CTO / Fullstack software engineer (Freelancer)

Developing BEEQUIP's (startup, fintech) online leasing platform from the ground up. Designed and implemented an information system (BEEHIVE) where we managed to capture the business processes and automated many of them. This system exposed a GraphQL API used by BEEQUIP's broker portal and customer portal. My best work to date as this was mainly a solo effort for 2 years. In 2018 this system processed 240 million leases in production. Tech used: Ruby on Rails, Python, TypeScript, Javascript, node.js, React, Apollo, Salesforce, Dynamics NAV, GraphQL, Docker, AWS, Continuous integration, Continuous delivery.

2015 - 2018, Backpackapp - CTO

Building a Travel agency platform for backpackers on the go, the challenge here lies in automated document classification and recognition. Tech used: Elixir, React native, Javascript (ES6)

2015 - 2016, Tele2 - Software Engineer (Freelancer)

Maintaining a software system used to commission and provision (4g) network devices. Developed consistency checking tool to audit network device configurations. Advance overall software quality by improving tests / software engineering practices. Tech used: Ruby, Rails, EventMachine, RabbitMQ, Backbone.js, MongoDB, Redis, Javascript, Docker.

2014 - 2016, Postinitial - CTO

Building an e-learning platform for Corporate Finance. Tech used: Ruby, Javascript, Rails, React.js, Flux, Docker

2008 - 2015, Kabisa, Software Engineer / lead / Devops / Consultant

Kabisa is specialised in developing elegant (enterprise) software solutions using technologies such as Ruby(on Rails) and Java. I have been with Kabisa since the start and have grown in to several roles such as scrum master, DevOps, lead developer, consultant, and software architect on a wide range of exciting projects for customers such as Philips, ViaViela B.V., Media Groep Limburg, Seacon Logistics and Yellobrick.

2007 - 2008, Philips

Internship where I developed an internet connected television prototype where users can share photo?s and play games over the internet.

Education

2008 - 2009, University of Amsterdam Master (MSc), Software engineering For my master's thesis, I researched Intelligent fuzzing of web applications.

2005 - 2008, Avans Hogeschool s-Hertogenbosch

- · Graduated cum laude
- Graduation internship at the Philips Innovation Lab worked on the European-funded Amigo project (http://www.hitech-projects.com/euprojects/amigo/)

Skills

Languages Dutch (mother tongue) German (basic) English (fluent) **Programming Languages** Ruby Rust o CSS Javascript / Typescript Python o (X)HTML / Flow / Node o Elixir SQL / Cypher o C++ Golang LaTex o Elm Java o Lua

Experience with frameworks/libraries

Ruby on RailsSinatra

RhomobileBackbone.js

o React / Redux / Apollo

Next.js / Express.js

o Apache Camel

Chef & Terrafrom

 $\circ \ \ Metasploit$

o Jupyter notebook

Software/Services

Linux (Debian/Ubuntu)

Git / Subversion

Mac OSX

o Adobe Photoshop

Adobe IllustratorAmazon EC2

o Kubernetes

Docker

o Github actions

o Jenkens CI

o Gitlab & Gitlab CI

o PostgreSQL / MySQL

o MongoDB

o Neo4J

o RabbitMQ

Additional Honors & Awards & Certificates

- o Graduated cum laude for bachelor degree computer science
- o Professional Scrum Master certificate (Scrum.org)
- o Coursera: Neural Networks and Deep Learning
- o Placed first at the RubyenRails 2009 rumble (http://2009.rubyenrails.nl/)